Guide to the Thomas Merton Center Records, 1962-2009 AIS.1982.19
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thomas Merton Center Records
1962-2009
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thomas Merton Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1982.19
88.83 Linear Feet (65 boxes and 2 reels of microfilm)
The Thomas Merton Center (TMC) of Pittsburgh is an affiliate of the International Thomas Merton Society. Growing out of Catholics in opposition to the Vietnam War, the TMC has since broadened its vision to encompass issues including nuclear weapons, South African apartheid, Central American counterinsurgencies, and crises in the Middle East. The material in this collection includes publications, subject files, pamphlets, correspondence, newsletters, and articles that reflect this wide array of activities.
History
In 1972, in part to protest the Catholic Church's silence during the Vietnam War, the Thomas Merton Center (TMC) of Pittsburgh was established, affiliating itself with the International Thomas Merton Society. In these early years, the TMC, named after a trappist monk and peace advocate, not only voiced opposition to the Vietnam War, but was also active locally in many other issues. Primary among these was the desire to fight racism and end poverty. To this end, the TMC helped establish the Jubilee Soup Kitchen, the Greater Pittsburgh Community Food Bank, and the Pittsburgh Chapter of Amnesty International.
During the following decade, the TMC increasingly worked toward raising awareness of the Nuclear Arms build-up and wars in Central America. Throughout the 1980s, the TMC protested corporations such as Rockwell, Westinghouse, and IBM (among others) for their relationship with the Department of Defense. The culmination of these efforts resulted in the River City Campaign, launched with the goal of abolishing nuclear weapons. This campaign took aim at increased defense spending as the TMC along with community activists held protests, teach-ins, and conducted acts of civil disobedience. In the midst of these activities, the TMC was also vocal in their opposition to American involvement in Central American political affairs and domestic insurgencies. In their Sister City Campaign, the TMC organized a Witness for Peace Program that linked Pittsburgh and San Isidro, Nicaragua.
In the 1990s, the TMC was active in protesting the first Gulf War and later the "Contract With America" legislation of 1994 and 1995. Also during this time, the Tri-State Conference on Steel and the Citizens Budget Campaigns worked in conjunction with the TMC to fight the loss of well-paid industrial jobs in the Pittsburgh region. In the 2000s, the TMC worked to abolish nuclear weapons, protested the War in Afghanistan and the Iraq War and advocated for economic justice in the region.
The Merton Center continues to publish its monthly newspaper The New People, a publication dedicated to addressing issues of war, poverty, racism and oppression around the world. The TMC remains active in pursuing issues that they deem central to peace and social justice, acting as a resource for other like-minded organizations throughout the region.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists of over 88 linear feet of material spanning from before the inception of the Thomas Merton Center in 1972 up to 2009. Materials in this collection are both regional and international in scope. Publications, subject files, pamphlets, correspondence, newsletters, and articles document the center's involvement and interest in political, social, and economic issues, such as women's rights, global poverty and inequality, and peaceful conflict resolution. Numerous other associations are represented in the records, including religious groups and non-governmental organizations (NGOs). The microfilm contains TMC and additional publications such as The New People, Update, Cease, and The Voice.
The records have been organized into series, reflecting periodic additions to the collection. More detailed scope and content notes are found at each series level. Series I, III, IV and V have large components of subject files, organized more or less alphabetically. Many subjects and activities are represented across multiple files and series. Researchers should search the collection widely for topics of interest.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Accruals
Additional material received in 1994, 2001, 2005 and 2009. Further accruals are expected.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Thomas Merton Center through Molly Rush in 1982.
Existence and Location of Copies note
A portion of the Thomas Merton Center records have been microfilmed; an inventory of this material is located in the Scope and Content Notes for the First Deposit.
Previous Citation
Thomas Merton Center Records, 1962-2009, AIS.1982.19, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following five series:
Series I. First Deposit (1982), 1971-1982
Series II. Second Deposit (1993), 1971-1993
Series III. Third Deposit (2000), 1977-2000
Series IV. Fourth Deposit (2004), 1983-2004
Series V. Fifth Deposit (2009), 1962-2009
Related Material
Pennsylvania Peace Links Records, 1981-2004, AIS.2004.09, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Pittsburgh Peace Institute Records, 1984-1997, AIS.1998.01, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Physicians for Social Responsibility, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1971-2004, AIS.2005.02, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Associations; Social action; Women; United States -- Politics and government -- 1974-1977; Labor; Unemployed; Gay rights; Equal rights amendments; Counterinsurgency -- Central America; Apartheid; Nuclear disarmament; Feminism; Thomas Merton Award; Civil rights; Capital punishment; Social justice; Race discrimination; International Women's Year, 1975; Hunger; War resistance movements; Employee rights; Price maintenance; Competition, Unfair; Giving, Charitable; East End Community Thrift (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company; Amnesty International USA. Pittsburgh Chapter; Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (Washington, D.C.); Citizens Budget Campaign of Western Pennsylvania; Greater Pittsburgh Community Food Bank; International Business Machines Corporation; Jubilee Soup Kitchen (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Merton, Thomas; River City Campaign; Rockwell International; Rush, Molly; Thomas Merton Society of Great Britain and Ireland; Tri-State Conference on Steel; Thomas Merton Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.). Giving Tree; Thomas Merton Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- First Deposit (1982), 1971-1982; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series holds administrative files from the organization of the center and subject files from the first ten years of its existence. The subject files are arranged mostly alphabetical by box and cover a wide range of topics. Much of the information here deals with Vietnam/Indochina, Jimmy Carter, world hunger, and opposition to the B-1 bomber. Extensive material pertaining to the International Year of the Woman (IYW) in 1977 is also found here.
  The two microfilm reels were also filmed in 1982. They contain chronologically arranged bulletins, election ballots, leaflets, announcements, and invitations to various activities, as well as several publications, including:
  The New People (monthly), v. 1, no. 1 - v. 11, no. 6 (February 1972 - June 1982)
  Update (an occasional mid-month bulletin), March 1973 - January 1975
  CEASE (Catholics for an End to Asian Slaughter and Exploitation - irregularly published), April 1972, December 1972, December 1973
  Seven Days of Light (by the Sisters' Council, Diocese of Pittsburgh and the Thomas Merton Center - annual), December 1972, December 1973
  The Voice (Committee on Women, Diocese of Pittsburgh), v. 2, no. 1-4 (October, December 1977, February, October 1978); v. 3, no. 1-3 (March, October, November 1979); v. 4, no. 1-2 (April, June 1980)
  Ballot, Annual Election of Board of Directors, April 1975 - April 1982
  - Microfilm (847 frames), February 1972-May 1980 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 3, Reel 1)
  - Microfilm (233 frames), June 1980-June 1982 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 3, Reel 2)
  - Advisory Board, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appeal Letter Addresses, April 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, The Thomas Merton Center, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board Members Nomination, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board Minutes Other Material, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - By-Laws (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Christmas, C.I.C.--Simple Christmas Gift Certificates, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Center Activities, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Call to Action, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chris Carroll, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - TMC Brochure, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Calendar, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - CCD Social Justice Course, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clergy Caucus, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Christmas, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 17-26)
  - Events, Merton Center, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Flea Market, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 28-32)
  - Giving Tree, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 33-35)
  - Lenten Sermons, Sent Out, February 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Letters of Recommendation for Proposals, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Mail-Incoming, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Merton Planning Committee, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Merton 7th Birthday Celebration, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Merton Center, June Witness, White House, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - News Releases--Conferences, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - News Releases from Merton Center, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Pittsburgh Legal Services--Clinic for Youth Proposals, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Positive Strokes for Center, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
  - TMC Publications, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Raskob Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Retreat, April 9-11, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Warrendale Retreat, October 1977 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Retreat, October 1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Betty Carroll Retreat, April 11-13, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Africa, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alert, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alliance to End Repression, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Alternatives, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Amnesty Week, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Amnesty, TMC Papers, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Amnesty, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Amnesty Homilies, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Angola, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Apartheid, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Appalachia, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Arms Control Seminar, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Arms Limitation, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bail, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bangladesh, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bishops on War, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Blacks--Legal Cases, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Blacks--Political Gains, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Black Studies, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brashear High School, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - James Carroll Retreat, May 12-14, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Warrendale Retreat, October 3-5, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Sermons, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Speakers, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - South Side Survey, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Staff Applications/Misc. Staff Info, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Staff Meetings, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
  - Steering Committee Job Applications, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - TMC Evaluation (Georgina Scarping), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - TAG Day for Hunger, April 21, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Urban Plunge, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Urban Plunge from Notre Dame, January 1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Inflation: A Moral Issue, April 7, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Elder-ado S.S. Program for Shut-ins, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Committee on Women, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Pittsburgh Power Structure, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Catholic Interracial Council, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - RRC, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - PAJE-Pa. Alliance on Jobs Energy, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Tag Days--TMC Events, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Women's Retreat, October 1976 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Signers of 10 Recommendations, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence (CW), 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Africa Rhodesia, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Brazil/Argentina, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Brazil, Dom Helder, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Buddhist Religious Writings, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Budget of the U.S., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Call to Action, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Financing Reform, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Carter Cabinet, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Catholic Church Renewal, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - News Releases from C.I.C. Statements, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Catholic Schools/Teachers, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Catholics for an End to Asian Slaughter and Exploitation (CEASE) - Newsletter, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chile, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chiquita Boycott, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - China, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Christmas, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Christianity Socialism, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Citizens for Nursing Home Reform, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Civil Rights, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Clinch River Breeder Reactor, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Coalition for Integrated Schools, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Congress War, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Congressional Voting Records, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Conscientious Objection, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Consumer Issues, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Continuing Education Series, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Corporations: Global Multi-Nationals, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Corporations Morality, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Counter Recruitment, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Corpus Christi Submarine, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Criminal Code Reform Act, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Criminal Justice, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Cuba, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Michael Cullen, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Desegregation, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Detente, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - D.C. Home Rule, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Divorce, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Dominican Republic, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Economic Information, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Ecumenical Witness, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Education, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Elder Citizens, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Daniel Ellsberg the Pentagon Papers, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Energy Crisis, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Environment, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Europe/Socialism, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fair Housing, USA, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Farah, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Free Ministry, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Eugene Gottesman, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fonda, Jane, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Policy Forum, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dick Gregory's Bicentennial Run, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Gulf Oil Corp. Demo, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Habitat, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - H.B. 50, Materials from Meetings, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - H.B. 50, Full Employment, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Harrisburg Defense Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - House Bills, Pennsylvania, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Health MCHR, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Holy Year, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Honeywell Materials, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hospitals, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Housing, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Human Development, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Human Love in Action, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Immigration, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Impeachment, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Indians, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Issues Today, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Ivan Illich, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - July 4 Demo, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Juvenile Detention Home, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Latin America, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Legislation, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Joanne Little, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Mail Outgoing--C.I.C., 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Mail Outgoing--Meals on Wheels, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - McGovern-Shriver, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Medical Committee for Human Rights, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Military Chaplains, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Ministers, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ministries to Military Personnel, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - George Mische, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Monthly Mission Donations, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Mozambique, 1973-1979 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Gary Myers (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - National Association of Laity (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - National Association of Laity, Peace Project Committee (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - New Economic Order (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New Yorker Editorials (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Richard Nixon (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nixon, Catholic Ethnics (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NOW (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Nuclear Power (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Nuclear Reactors (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Nyden, Paul, Committee to Defind (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Tom O'Brien (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Overview (Catholic publication) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pacifism (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Panama Canal Treaty (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Paris Peace Talks (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Catholic Committee on Urban Ministry (CCUM), Pastoral Workshop on Appalachia (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Patient's Rights (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Peace Agreement (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Peace Symbol (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Philippines (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Pittsburgh Committee for Human Rights (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Pittsburgh Pilgrimage Planning Committee (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Pittsburgh School Desegregation Project (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Police (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Pope John Paul II, Karol Wojtyla (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Poverty in America (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Prisoners Strike for Peace (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Revenue Sharing (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Right to Work Laws (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Rockwell Lawsuit (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
  - S-1 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Sacred Design (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - School Districts, Pgh. City Schools (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Selling of the Pentagon Papers (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Share (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Social concerns (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Soviet Jewry Issues (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Spain (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - J.P. Stevens Boycott (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Strip Mining (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sun Day (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Team Ministry (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Third World (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tuition Relief Legislation (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Uganda (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Unemployment (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - United Farm Workers (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
  - Urban Pastoral (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Vatican--Justice in the World (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Voluntary Job Preservation Community Stabilization (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Voting Records: Legislators (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - War Resistance (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Watergate (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - WDUQ (Radio station) Communications Advisory Council (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Welfare (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Welfare Reform, the Carter Proposals (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Welfare Rights Coalition (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Western Pa. Coalition for Children's Survival (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Western 23 for PHRC 17 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - White House Prayer Group (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Wilmington 10 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Witness Against Execution (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Wounded Knee (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - WYEP (Radio station) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Zimbawe Eight (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Zimbabwe Students/CMU (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Zionism (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - American Freedom from Hunger Foundation (AFFHF) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Africa - Famine (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - America Friends Service Committee-Hunger (AFSC) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Agribusiness (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Allegheny County (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Alternate Diets (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Asia (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Audio-Visual on Hunger (in Pittsburgh) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Baptists (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Beef Production Consumption (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bibliography (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bread for the World (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Press Coverage (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Care (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Catholic Church - World Hunger (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Climate - World Hunger (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Community Nutrition Institute (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Cooperatives (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Christian Relief Overseas Project (CROP) (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Catholic Relief Services (CRS) (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Environment (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - FAO (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Famine (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Fasting (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Fertilizer Energy (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Food--Consumer (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Food Day, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 28-31)
  - Food Education (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Food for Peace (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Food--Justice (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Food Policy (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Food Project (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Food Stamps Hunger in America (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Forecasts, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Foreign Aid (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - General Information--Food Shortage (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Global Village (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Grain Reserves/Trade (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Growth--Development (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Hunger Action Coalition (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
  - Increased Yields of Crops (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Inflation (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Institution of Social Relations, Newark Diocese (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Interreligious Task Force (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Land Use (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Latin America (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Lifeboat Ethics (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Lifestyles (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Local National Organizations (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Meatless Meals (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Molly's "Stuff" (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - National Council of Churches (Christian Associates) (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - National Catholic Rural Life Conference (NCRLC) (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Nutrition Info (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Operation Rice Bowl (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - PAN--World Food Conference Newsletter (WF) (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Pests: Food Storage (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Practical Suggestions (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Project Bread (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Proper Diet (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Simple Lifestyles (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - UNICEF (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - U.S. Catholic Conference (USCC) (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - U.S. Government (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - World Hunger Action Coalition (WHAC) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - World Food Conference (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Food Policies (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Macro Series (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Population (Articles) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - World Food (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - World Hunger Week, 1974-1977 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
  - World Hunger Awareness Week, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hunger Slide Show, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hunger Info, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Bread for the World (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hunger--Prayer--Liturgy (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Molly Rush--Draft of Slide Show (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Molly's Slide Show--Clippings (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Misc Clippings, Pamphlets, Papers (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
  - Stop B-1 Efforts of Other Cities (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Slide Show (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Tax Day B-1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Packet (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Air Force (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - B-1 Bomber News, Fall 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Efforts (Box 9, Folder 7)